<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Humber Analytics - Python, AWS, MySQL, Databases, Web Services</title><link href="https://humberanalytics.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://humberanalytics.com/feeds/python-aws-mysql-databases-web-services.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://humberanalytics.com/</id><updated>2019-06-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Building a Database of Prices Paid for UK Residential Property on Amazon Web Services</title><link href="https://humberanalytics.com/Building-a-Database-of-Prices-Paid-for-UK-Residential-Property-on-Amazon-Web-Services.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-06-24T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-06-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dan Humphreys</name></author><id>tag:humberanalytics.com,2019-06-24:/Building-a-Database-of-Prices-Paid-for-UK-Residential-Property-on-Amazon-Web-Services.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This post describes how to create a database of prices paid for UK residential properties on Amazon Web Services (AWS).&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Building a Database of Price Paid Data for UK Properties on Amazon Web Services&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post describes how a database of the prices paid for UK property can be created on Amazon Web Services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is the first in a series of 3 posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sign up for Amazon Web Services (AWS)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven't got one already you will need to register for a new account with &lt;a href="https://portal.aws.amazon.com/billing/signup#/start"&gt;Amazon Web Services&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="images/post1.png" height="400" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have registered AWS provides a number of services you can access for free as described &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/free/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  INcidentally AWS will ask you for some credit/debit card details which you will need to provide to register successfully.  Don't worry since you should be able to follow this tutorial using the free tier resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Install AWS CLI&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than use the AWS GUI available when you log in we'll manage our instances using the AWS CLI  which enables you to fully manage your AWS cloud resources via terminal commands.  Therefore you will also need to down &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="posts"></category></entry></feed>